Guide to the UE National Office Records Relating to District 4 and District 4 Locals, 1935-1991 UE.4.1.4
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- District 4 Locals, 2.
  - Local 1227
    - Local 1227 Correspondence and Reports, December 1941-May 1955 (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - Morey Machine Shop Resolution Regarding Factionalism, January 1947; 16.
      - Frank Chacon to Local 1227 Regarding Factionalism, February 17, 1947; 17.
      - Notification of Pending Disagreement Regarding Morey Machine Company, February 18, 1947; 18.
      - Report of Delegate to Assemblyman Levine, April 1947; 19.
      - Notification of Pending Disagreement Regarding General Register, March 24, 1947; 20.
      - Perillo Staff Application with April 1, 1947, James Garry Letter to UE, March 28, 1947; 21.
      - Selma Memo to Paula Regarding Staff Members, April 29, 1947; 22.
      - Bill Rubens to Jim Regarding Acco Products Runaway Shops, July 2, 1947; 23.
      - Unsigned Letter to Phillip Murray Regarding Political Action with Bruno Andrews Letter to Albert Fitzgerald, January 8, 1948; 24.
      - Dance Greeting, January 1949; 25.
      - Report of Sub-Committee on Unemployment, April 6, 1949; 26.
      - Sara Malloy to Emspak Regarding Finances, May 25, 1949; 27.
      - Memo Regarding Local 1227 Sklar Strike, August 23, 1949; 28.
      - Resolution of the Minority on Peace, February 1, 1951; 29.
      - History of the IUE Raid with March 27, 1951, Emma Memo to Bertha, 30.
      - Dance Greeting, April 9, 1951; 31.
      - Elm Memo to David Ratner Regarding Finances, November 23, 1954; 32.
      - Matles to Al Burdick Regarding Anti-Communism, May 18, 1955; 33.
    - Local 1227 Pamphlets, 1941-1950 (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - But for the Grace of God Regarding Premier Metal Etching Firings with April 30, 1941, Louis Kricker Letter, 1.
      - To All Sisters and Brothers Regarding Officers and Factionalism, 1941; 2.
      - Today, the Boom Regarding Organization, 1941; 3.
      - Disputes Before the War Labor Board, April 1944; 4.
      - Annual Dance Program, March 6, 1948; 5.
      - Annual Dance, March 4, 1950; 6.
    - Local 1227 Leaflets, 1941-1949 (Box 12, Folder 41)
      - "Today It's Your Choice" Regarding Officers and Factionalism, 1941; 1.
      - "Communist Party" Regarding Officers and Factionalism, 1941; 2.
      - "Kollsman Workers" Regarding International Association of Machinist Inter-union Rivalry with James Garry Letter to James Matles, July 2, 1942; 3.
      - "Remember Pearl Harbor" Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, April 1, 1948; 4.
      - "Merry Xmas and Happy New Year" Regarding Congress of Industrial Organizations Inter-union Rivalry, December 22, 1949; 5.
      - "In the Past Few Months" Regarding Unemployment, March 14, 1949; 6.
      - "Local Meeting" Regarding Unemployment, March 31, 1949; 7.
    - Local 1227 Newspaper Clippings, July 18, 1940-June 17, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 42)
      - "Queens Employers See Labor Data," New York Times, July 18, 1940; 1.
      - "1800 at War Rally Revve Town Meeting", June 17, 1943; 2.
      - "Legion Award to Rabbi Schultz" with J.T. Memo to Selma, 3.
    - Local 1227 Press Releases, January 29-February 14, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 43)
      - Press Release Regarding Local 1227 Morey Machinery Contract with January 30, 1940, Ben Polsky Letter to UE News, January 29, 1940; 1.
      - Press Release Regarding Local 1227 Morey Machinery Contract, February 14, 1940; 2.
    - Local 1227 Newspapers, November 18, 1941-September 23, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 44)
      - Kollsman UE News, November 18, 1941; 1.
      - Activities Bulletin, September 23, 1942; 2.
    - Local 1227 Photo, May Day, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Local 1230
    - Local 1230 Constitution, Projector Craftsman By-laws, December 16, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Local 1230 Incoming Correspondence, March 4, 1938-March 3, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 47)
      - Julius Emspak to Thomas F. Collins Regarding By-laws, March 4, 1938; 1.
      - Emspak to Frank Meyer Regarding Re-instatements, March 24, 1938; 2.
      - Emspak to Meyer Regarding Enclosed Check, March 29, 1938; 3.
      - Emspak to Collins Regarding By-laws, April 14, 1938; 4.
      - Emspak to Collins Regarding Tickets, April 20, 1938; 5.
      - Emspak to Collins Regarding Letterhead, April 20, 1938; 6.
      - Emspak to Meyer Regarding Dues and Stamps, June 6, 1938; 7.
      - Emspak to Joseph Turek Regarding Constitution, October 20, 1938; 8.
      - Emspak to Turek Regarding Stamps, October 24, 1938; 9.
      - Emspak to Turek Regarding Mailing List, November 3, 1938; 10.
      - Emspak to Charles Rousseau Regarding Shop Organization, January 25, 1939; 11.
      - Emspak to Rousseau Regarding Meeting, March 3, 1939; 12.
      - Nathan Geller to H. Schnettler Regarding Meeting, November 11, 1938; 13.
      - William Mitchell to Collins Regarding Contracts, April 28, 1938; 14.
    - Local 1230 Outgoing Correspondence, February 7, 1938-March 2, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 48)
      - Thomas Collins to National Headquarters Regarding By-laws, February 7, 1938; 1.
      - Collins to Julius Emspak Regarding By-laws, April 12, 1938; 2.
      - Collins to Emspak Regarding Dance, April 12, 1938; 3.
      - Collins to International Office Regarding Contract, April 20, 1938; 4.
      - Collins to Emspak Regarding Forward Correspondence, April 19, 1938; 5.
      - Collins to Emspak Regarding Election, June 20, 1938; 6.
      - Joseph Turek to National Office Regarding By-laws, October 18, 1938; 7.
      - Turek to Emspak Regarding Stamps, October 21, 1938; 8.
      - The Committee to Emspak Regarding Tickets with Tickets, April 4, 1938; 9.
      - Frank Meyer to Emspak Regarding Error, March 11, 1938; 10.
      - Meyer to Emspak Regarding Letterhead, May 14, 1938; 11.
      - Meyer to Emspak Regarding Address Change, May 30, 1938; 12.
      - Charles Rousseau to Emspak Regarding Information, January 25, 1939; 13.
      - Rousseau to James Matles Regarding Rates with Rates, February 17, 1939; 14.
      - Rousseau to Emspak Regarding List, January 5, 1939; 15.
      - Rousseau to Emspak Regarding Meeting, March 2, 1939; 16.
      - H. Schnettler to Emspak Regarding Mailing List and Stamps, November 6, 1938; 17.
  - Local 1233
    - Local 1233 Incoming Correspondence, March 1, 1938-January 26, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 49)
      - Julius Emspak to Robert Ward Regarding People's Press, March 1, 1938; 1.
      - Emspak to Ward Regarding Financial Problems, May 9, 1938; 2.
      - Emspak to Ward Regarding Information, June 6, 1938; 3.
      - Emspak to Arthur Hechchel Regarding Amendments Passed, October 26, 1938; 4.
      - Emspak to Ward Regarding Re-instatement, April 26, 1939; 5.
      - James Matles to Hechchel Regarding Wage Rages, January 26, 1939; 6.
    - Local 1233 Outgoing Correspondence, March 3, 1938-March 25, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 50)
      - Robert Ward to Julius Emspak Regaridng Financial Dififculties, March 3-May 4, 1938; 1-2
      - Ward to Emspak Regarding Financial Report, May 10, 1938; 3.
      - Ward to Emspak Regarding Rates, June 1, 1938; 4.
      - Ward to Emspak Regarding Constitution, March 25, 1939; 5.
    - Local 1233 Financial Secretary Reports, February 1938-June 1939 (Box 12, Folder 51)
    - Local 1223 Brooklyn American Machine and Foundry, June 6, 1937-February 16, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Local 1234
    - Local 1234 Incoming Correspondence, April 13-December 29, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 53)
      - Julius Emspak to Howard Staudt Regarding Locals Merger, December 29, 1939; 1.
      - Emspak to William Mitchell Regarding Recalled Charter with Notice of Suspension, April 13, 1939; 2.
    - Local 1234 Outgoing Correspondence, October 21-December 22, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 54)
      - William Gilbert to Julius Emspak Regarding Amalgamation, December 22, 1938; 1.
      - Muriel Weitz to Brother Regarding Re-directed Mail, October 21, 1938; 2.
    - Local 1234 Brooklyn National Seal and Gutman, August 4, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Local 1234 Brooklyn National Seal and Gutman, September 24, 1937-August 16, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Local 1236
    - Local 1236 Brooklyn Micamold Radio Corporation, September 2-December 24, 1937 (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Local 1237
    - Local 1237 Officers Lists, April 27, 1938-June 1, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Local 1237 Membership Resolutions, December 1940-May 1947 (Box 12, Folder 59)
      - Underwood Negotiations with December 26, 1940, W. Boutton Letter to James Carey, December 1940; 1.
      - Civil Rights Congress with Resolution on Civil Liberties, May 13, 1947; 2.
    - Local 1237 Incoming Correspondence, March 18, 1938-March 19, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 60)
      - James Carey to William B. Boulton Regarding Invitation, February 15, 1939; 1.
      - Carey to Nicholas Pellegrino Regarding Dance, March 7, 1939; 2.
      - Carey to Eugene Searles Regarding Invitation, December 18, 1939; 3.
      - A. Chorba to Sidney Gilbert Regarding Pittsburgh Dictophone, October 4, 1941; 4.
      - Julius Emspak to A.W. Neergaard Regarding Per Capita and Payments, March 18, 1938; 5.
      - Emspak to J.K. Landa Regarding Group Information, April 12, 1938; 6.
      - Emspak to Edward F. McCauley Regarding Misinterpretation, December 22, 1938; 7.
      - Emspak to Pellegrino Regarding Invitation, March 15, 1939; 8.
      - Emspak to Sidney Gilbert Regarding Enclosed Letter, May 24, 1939; 9.
      - Emspak to Local 1237 Regardng Dues, August 28, 1939; 10.
      - Emspak to McCauley Regarding Dues, October 16, 1939; 11.
      - Emspak to Herbert C. Kaswinkle Regarding Thank You Letter, November 10, 1939; 12.
      - Emspak to Gilbert Regarding Constitution Draft, December 5, 1939; 13.
      - Emspak to Boulton Regarding List, October 10, 1940; 14.
      - Emspak to Boulton Regarding Mailing List, November 1, 1940; 15.
      - Emspak to Boulton Regarding Debt, February 17-April 3, 1941; 16-17.
      - Emspak to Boulton Regarding Mailing List, May 29, 1941; 18.
      - Emspak to Boulton Regarding Fees, June 15, 1941; 19.
      - Emspak to Boulton Regarding UE Constitution, Per Capita and Factionalism, February 9, 1944; 20.
      - Emspak to Boulton Regarding Late Letter, July 9, 1945; 21.
      - Emspak to UE Regarding Appointment, March 19, 1948; 22.
      - Emspak to Neergaard Regarding Communications, May 12, 1938; 23.
      - Nathan Geller to McCauley Regarding Schedule, November 11, 1938; 24.
      - S. Kelly to Gilbert Regarding Error, March 10, 1939; 25.
      - Verne Kennedy to Gilbert Regarding Constitutions, April 6, 1939; 26.
    - Local 1237 Incoming Correspondence, May 11, 1938-March 24, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 61)
      - James Matles to William Boulton Regarding Notification of Pending Disagreement, January 20, 1939; 1.
      - Matles to Sidney Gilbert Regarding Pending Disagreement, February 10-March 10, 1939; 2-3.
      - Matles to Gilbert Regarding Business Machine Mechanics, September 13, 1939; 4.
      - Matles to Boulton Regarding Affidavit, November 21, 1939; 5.
      - Matles to Edward McCauley Regarding Return Credentials, December 29, 1939; 6.
      - Matles to Vincent J. Donnelly Regarding Pending Disagreement, April 18, 1940; 7.
      - Matles to Gilbert Regarding Recommendations with Business Relations, September 17, 1940; 8.
      - Matles to Albert Luckett Regarding Underwood Contracts and Internatioal Association of Machinists Inter-union Rivalry, October 23, 1941; 9.
      - Matles to Edward Timmes Regarding Organization, October 27, 1941; 10.
      - Matles to Timmes Regarding Remmington Rand New York Negotiations, November 13, 1941; 11.
      - Matles to Luckett Regarding Military Production, February 17, 1942; 12.
      - Matles to Joseph Nieroda Regarding Organization, February 25, 1943; 13.
      - Matles to Nieroda Regarding Service Shops Organization, March 19, 1943; 14.
      - Matles to Nieroda Regarding Membership Meeting, March 24, 1943; 15.
      - William Mitchell to A. Neergaard Regarding Organizing, May 11, 1938; 16.
    - Local 1237 Outgoing Correspondence, March 15, 1938-December 17, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 62)
      - R. Beisiegel to James Matles Regarding Holidays, July 9, 1943; 1.
      - William Boulton to James Carey Regarding Elections, February 11, 1939; 2.
      - Boulton to Carey Regarding American Federtaion of Labor Inter-union Rivalry and Factionalism, November 18, 1940; 3.
      - Boulton to Carey Regarding Underwood Negotiations, January 28, 1941; 4.
      - Boulton to Julius Emspak Regarding Payments, May 15, 1941; 5.
      - Boulton to Emspak Regarding Finances and Staff Members, August 15, 1941; 6.
      - Boulton to Emspak Regarding Officers, August 9, 1943; 7.
      - Boulton to Emspak Regarding Per Capita, January 22-February 3, 1944; 8-9.
      - Boulton to Emspak Regarding Per Capita and Factionalism, February 14, 1944; 10.
      - Boulton to Emspak Regarding Officers, August 11, 1944; 11.
      - Boulton to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Factionalism, November 6, 1944; 12.
      - Boulton to Emspak Regarding Stamps, June 14, 1945; 13.
      - Boulton to Emspak Regarding Policy Confusion, June 21, 1945; 14.
      - Boulton to James McLeish Regarding Union Laws, December 17, 1947; 15.
      - Edward Burns to UE Regarding Elections, March 29, 1939; 16.
      - Burns to Herbert Lehman Regarding Legislation Signature, May 12, 1939; 17.
      - James Conroy to Mitchell Regarding Elections, July 26, 1939; 18.
      - Vincent Donnelly to Franklin D. Roosevelt Regarding Rescind Appointment, July 11, 1940; 19.
      - Sid Gilbert to Emspak Regarding UE News, July 5, 1940; 20.
      - Gilbert to Matles Regarding Relations, October 8, 1940; 21.
      - Gilbert to Tom Molloy Regarding Local 251 Hartford Royal Strike with Gilbert Letter to Matles, December 27, 1940; 22.
      - Albert Locket to UE News Regarding UE News and Factionalism, August 3, 1941; 23.
      - Locket to A. Chorba Regarding AFL Dictaphone Negotiations with Locket Letter to Matles, October 8, 1941; 24.
      - Locket to Matles Regarding Underwood Negotiations and War Production Board, February 10, 1942; 25.
      - Locket to Matles Regarding Woodstock Typewriter Contracts, May 26, 1942; 26.
      - A. Neergaard to Emspak Regarding Discontinuation of People's Press for Local, March 14, 1938; 27.
      - Neergaard to Emspak Regarding Information, April 9, 1938; 28.
      - Neergaard to UE Regarding Union Mechanics, May 9, 1938; 29.
      - Joseph Nieroda to Matles Regarding Organization, February 16, 1943; 30.
      - Nieroda to Matles Regarding Service Shops Organization, March 1, 1943; 31.
      - Nieroda to Edward Matthews Regarding Service Shops, March 20, 1943; 32.
      - Nicholas Pellegrino to Carey Regarding Tickets with Tickets, March 4, 1939; 33.
      - Pellegrino to Emspak Regarding Tickets, March 4, 1939; 34.
      - Pellegrino to Matles Regarding Tickets, March 4, 1939; 35.
      - Eugene Searles to UE Regarding Forms, November 16, 1938; 36.
      - Searles to Matles Regarding Agreement Copies, February 13, 1939; 37.
      - Searles to Carey Regarding Membership Meeting, December 7, 1939; 38.
      - Edward Timmes to Matles Regarding Remmington Rand Organization, October 22-November 10, 1941; 39-40.
      - Timmes to Fitzgerald Regarding Factionalism, November 21, 1944; 41.
      - Timmes to Emspak Regarding Request, September 4, 1946; 42.
    - Local 1237 Salary and Expense Letters, William Boulton, December 26, 1940-May 13, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 63)
    - Local 1237 Finances, January 17, 1939-March 29, 1947 (Box 12, Folder 64)
    - Local 1237 Decca Strikes, October 31-November 5, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 65)
      - William Mitchell Telegram to McCarthy, October 31, 1938; 1.
      - Decca Records Statement, November 5, 1938; 2.
    - Local 1237 Underwood Labor Spies, April 17-19, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 66)
      - Allen Sayler to James Carey, April 17, 1940; 1.
      - Carey to Sayler, April 19, 1940; 2.
    - Local 1237 Amalgamation, April 19-28, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 67)
      - James McLeish to Julius Emspak, April 19, 1949; 1.
      - Edward Washington to McLeish, April 20, 1949; 2.
      - McLeish to Emspak, April 28, 1949; 3.
      - Sidney Gilbert to McLeish, April 5, 1949; 4.
    - Local 1237 Correspondence and Statements, 1941-1944 (Box 12, Folder 68)
      - Financial Statement, 1941; 1.
      - Inter-local Committee for Progressive Trade Unionism Statement, 1941; 2.
      - War Labor Board Order Regarding Undrewood, March 19, 1943; 3.
      - Ed Matthews Memo Regarding Sharon Strike and Factionalism, April 3, 1943; 4.
      - Julius Emspak to James Mustig Regarding Per Capita, May 31, 1944; 5.
    - Local 1237 Pamphlets, 1947-1948 (Box 12, Folder 69)
      - Answer to Local 1237 Regarding Factionalism, September 9, 1947; 1.
      - Truth Will Out Regarding Factionalism, 1948; 2.
    - Local 1237 Leaflets, February 18-April 12, 1948 (Box 12, Folder 70)
      - "Why Did They Hide the Truth" Regarding Factionalism, February 13, 1948; 1.
      - "Rem Rand Workers Need Raise Now" Regarding Factionalism, February 20, 1948; 2.
      - "Vote Tomorrow" Regarding Local 1237 Officers and Factionalism, February 26, 1948; 3.
      - "It Is Now Four Months" Regarding Factionalism, April 12, 1948; 4.
      - "RR Offers Wage Increase" Regarding Factionalism, 1948; 5.
    - Local 1237 Press Release Regarding Factionalism and Officers, June 1941 (Box 12, Folder 71)
    - Local 1237 New York City Typewriter and Business Machines, September 20, 1937-February 19, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 72)
    - Local 1237 New York City Typewriter and Business Machines, November 1, 1937-August 26, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 73)